Welcome to a video where we'll be
building a full project from not even
having an idea all the way to having a
live app that I would be and will be
actually using in my business. And if
you wanted, you could even monetize this
ad payments and sell this as a SAS
product. So, what are we going to be
building today? And what kind of tools
will we use in the process? So, we're
going to build a little application that
I call the Qboard, which allows content
creators to create custom question and
answer boards for their audience. Now,
as you can see, this app is still very
simple, but that's because we're going
to be doing the full build in this
YouTube video, all the way from
generating the idea to having this live
on the internet with functional
authentication and the core feature
enabled. As you'll see throughout this
video, it's really simple to expand it
and to add other things and improve the
design, but I really wanted to show you
a full workflow that would help a lot of
people in just going for it and building
their very first thing.
>> Do it.
>> Because getting to this point is doable
for everybody with just a few steps. as
I'll outline them in this video. The
tool stack that we'll be using and the
accounts that you will need to follow
along this tutorial are the following.
First, I'll list the tools and then I'll
explain why. First and foremost, we'll
be using Lovable to build this site.
We'll be using Sappase for the database
that will store all the user data. We'll
be using a combination of Claude and
Gemini for the ideation. And that is it.
That's literally all you need. You can
complete all of this on the free
accounts with the exception of the
Gemini Deep Research that I will be
running. But that is not absolutely
necessary. Everything else I do in here,
you can do on the free accounts here.
So, why are we using this tool stack?
Well, first and foremost, Lovable
partnered with us on this video. And I
couldn't be more excited about this
partnership because if you've been
following, you might have noticed that
Lovable took this development space by
storm. And I want to make one thing
clear and this is independent of the
sponsorship. If you're not aware,
there's a spectrum of these AI builder
tools. Okay? On the one side of the
spectrum, there's ease of use, and on
the other side of the spectrum, there's
the ones that are harder to use, but
they give you the maximum amount of
manual control. Now, I think it could be
debated what's on this side of the
spectrum, but one thing is clear.
Lovable is on this side of the spectrum,
meaning it is the ideal application for
people to get into vibe coding. There's
no simpler interface than this because,
as you can see, you can pick templates
that they already have, or you can start
from scratch, as we're doing in this
video, and it'll just build the whole
thing for you. You don't have to worry
about connecting everything up. You
don't have to worry about using a
command line interface. It just works.
And that's also the reason why this
thing went so viral recently. And with
their new agent mode, which is the
reason they're sponsoring this video,
for me to show you how well that works,
it became even more intuitive as you'll
see in this video. So, that's lovable. I
highly recommend that tool even outside
of the sponsorship. Sappase is just kind
of the golden standard for user
databases, especially for newcomers. You
just create an account and link it up in
lovable as we'll do later in this video
and then voila you have user
authentication and then we'll be using a
combination of Gemini deep research and
claude to generate an idea. I'll show
you my entire process there and as
you'll see in that part I'll also reveal
my methodology as how I generate ideas
with the help of AI these days. Okay, so
with that being said, if you have those
accounts set up, really all you need is
one LLM, free lovable account and a free
supper account. We're ready to get into
this tutorial and we're going to
generate an idea and build a full
application from scratch. Let's do it.
Okay, so let's start by finding our
idea. And obviously we're going to be
doing this with the help of AI. Now, as
a starting point, we'll be using this
relatively simple prompt to find various
ideas. But as opposed to some of the
news videos we do, in this one, I'm
actually going to show you the full
process of how I would be doing this and
what tools I would be using when I'm
actually building something and not just
doing a quick demo. So here's the simple
prompt to get things started. I want to
generate five unique web app ideas that
meet these criteria. Then here I just
have a few criteria that resonated with
me and various target audiences that I
can imagine building something for
because I understand them as I am a part
of these target audiences. So two things
we have to consider. One, the LLM
platform and tool that we'll be doing
this with. So first things first, let's
talk about the prompt. Practically when
I have prompts that really matter, I use
one of two tools. Sam the prompt creator
that we built ourselves that is free to
use on the GBD store that I go to super
often because it's freely available and
super quick to access. But when it comes
to development specific tasks, I usually
use Enthropics prompt improver. So
inside the Enthropic console, I navigate
to this button that says generate a
prompt and then in here I can kind of
put in what I already have. Make sure to
check this which says that I'll be using
a thinking model which I definitely will
and then I hit generate. Now, the neat
thing about this is that this is kind of
optimized for development and it will
flash this out in great detail. And what
I'll do next is I'll review this prompt
and delete parts that I find irrelevant.
So, let me just manually do that and
I'll see you in a second.
>> A few moments later.
>> And there you go. Actually, changing
this didn't take much. All I did is
replace the year variables with a
concrete year 2025. I added some context
on what I will be doing with this app,
which is building something for a
YouTube video. and everything it added
here. This five-step process for how to
generate the idea and the output format
actually really like. I just kept it as
is. So, what I'm going to do is I'm
going to copy this refined prompt. And
now we get to the idea generation part.
So, practically when it comes to
generating ideas with LLMs, I have very
specific preferences. For ideas, I
personally prefer both Gemini and
Claude. And because I work a ton in
Claude, that's usually what I default
to. But when I run deep researches,
which is what we're going to be doing
here, usually when I run deep
researches, I run them in multiple
engines. And now after multiple months,
I can just say this confidently. A bit
more nuanced or a bit more relevant.
Deep research in Gemini. Amazing. So I'm
going to open up Gemini here, paste my
prompt, enable deep research, and run
this. And then practically, usually I
can't help myself and I and because I
pay for multiple platforms, I just run
this for multiple deep researches. And
at this stage, now that we refined our
prompt and we're running a deep
research, we can take a step back, go or
do something else. And I'll see you in a
second where we'll be reviewing some of
these ideas and then taking one of those
ideas and actually turning it into app
with lovable. 5 minutes later.
>> Okay, so around 5 minutes in, Google's
deep research is still searching the web
and preparing this. It's almost done,
but the clawed one is ready to go. So,
let's start by reviewing these and see
what we like. Meeting fairness, the time
zone equity tracker for remote teams.
Okay. Visualize team availability across
time zones with a simple heat map and
then track the inconvenient meeting
count. Okay, that's kind of cool. What
else we got? AI powered crossplatform
content adapter. Okay, so these things
exist, but honestly this one could be
interesting if it would give you options
to customize it for yourself. I know. I
would like a platform like that where I
could tinker with the prompts.
Interesting. Interesting. Invoice nudge.
Automated payment reminder systems. Uh,
okay. Burnout block. Meeting fatigue
prevention tool. Browser extension that
analyzes your calendar. How about local
boost DIY local SEO checker? So from
these I like meeting fairness a lot
because it could be a tool where you
could customize it for your team and
then you get a custom map of the world
showing all your team members. I like
that a lot. Now let's compare that with
some of the Google Gemini ideas which
yes are complete by now. And as you can
see it upheld the template here
extremely well. It's exactly what I told
it to. No extra formatting just the
format that I want. So yeah amongst high
relevance also prompt adherence in
Gemini's deep research. It's just one of
the reasons that makes this the best
deep research right now. Okay. Name of
the app, Sign Off. It's for remote
workers and it's a minimalist
progressive web app designed to
facilitate a clear and stress-free end
to the workday. Oh, that's interesting.
So, it's kind of a end of day journaling
thing. Helping people to unplug.
Interesting. What about another one?
Nicheinder AI content creators strategic
market analysis tool that identifies
content gaps on video platforms like
YouTube. Ah, there's tools that do this
better already. How about this one?
Local, easy, small business owners. A
hyper local marketing assistant designed
for time poor entrepreneurs. Okay. A
business owner completes a one-time
setup and a few keywords describing
their brand voice to generate marketing
copy. The user simply provides a brief
goal. The app uses the Google Maps API
to pull relevant local context and
combines it with the saved profile
information, a specific goal. Okay, this
one's actually a great idea, but I think
it goes beyond the scope of today's
video. I like this one a lot though. And
then too long didn't watch a personal
productivity utility. A single page web
app where users can paste a public or
unlisted URL from a video platform like
Loom or YouTube or paste a large block
of text from a Slack thread or email.
And then it uses AI to summarize it.
Okay, that's solid. What about this one?
Qboard for content creators. Q&A app
that streamlines audience interaction
for video creators. A creator generates
a unique sharable Qboard link for a
specific video or for their channel as a
whole. place the link in the video
description and promote it to their
audience. And then viewers can submit
questions and upload questions posted by
others. Okay, I actually personally love
this one. I was thinking of doing
something like this for my videos. And I
think there's tools out there that do it
already, but they're not very
customizable from what I know. And if I
built this, I could add all sorts of
features to this and really tailor it to
myself and then maybe eventually to
others, too. So, I'm going to go with
this idea. And can you see the
difference between these ideas already?
Like these are quick doable ideas, but
let's be honest, I don't think none of
these would be suitable to actually
build a business on where I feel like
these deep research ideas, especially
this one like local E toz where it
localizes all the marketing to Google
maps data. Like these are real ideas
that if you build them out, you could
start building a legitimate business on
top of just this where the claw ideas
are more like something to try,
something fun. And to round out this
preparation part of the video, I'm
actually going to return to this claude
thread here. I don't have deep research
enabled anymore, but I actually want to
use Opus to flesh out this idea. And the
reason I'm going to do it in this thread
is because it has context on what I'm
doing already. I'm just going to ask it
to spec out this app so I can give
something concrete to Lovable. And just
to be clear at this point, you could
just go in and give Lovable one sentence
and it will build the thing for you. But
yeah, if you go through this process,
it's going to be less trial and error.
And I just like fleshing out my vision
in advance before I actually get into
building. But yeah, you could actually
skip all this and if you just have an
idea, you could type in a sentence.
Boom, get the app built and then work
from there. So, I'm just going to tell
it where I'm at that I have an idea and
where I need to go, which is the no code
builder. And then I just get a bit more
specific with telling it what exactly
I'm expecting from it. Okay, so quick
look over this user types. So, as you
can see, this is very, very specific,
which might not always be a good thing
because it's specified every single
thing. But I'm just going to copy this
entire thing, move over to Lovable, and
if you're logged in on a free account,
you can already build things, and their
new agent mode is enabled by default.
So, I'm just going to paste in this
detail prompt, and run this.
Okay. And as I log in, I just create a
brand new project to store all of the
user and login information. And then
back here in Lovable, I just click
connect to that project. And there you
go. Now I connected it and Lovable can
proceed with actually using the database
on suppend
of my app and store all of the user
data. Okay, now that we have that, I can
just say continue.
>> A few moments later.
>> Okay, so just after five credits, which
I did fully on the free account, I have
a website that does the core of what was
described. Okay. And after implementing
some of these security fixes, it
recommended here we're ready to publish
this project. So I guess I could do two
more security fixes, but I just want to
see it in action now.
Ah, and as of right now, all these
buttons give me four or four errors.
It's interesting. Sometimes when I open
it, it works. And we're just going to go
with that because things like this
happen when you vibe code. You just need
to point out what happened and message
like all the website buttons give me 44.
Oops. Page not found. and then it will
find a way to fix that. And as you can
see, it's already fixing the missing
routes and pages. Okay, let's just make
sure to update the website with these
changes. And then when I refresh the
site, I can go to sign in. And voila, it
already hit my previous session where I
logged in and I see my interface. So, as
you see this working through it, what
you might notice is that it's doing
multiple steps. And this is the new
agent mode. And it doesn't just make the
code more precise with way less bugs
being included than before. It can
actually search the entire codebase,
locate exact files through agentic
search, meaning the agent just looks for
everything and finds the parts that are
relevant to it and then works on those.
It can also search the webs, create
screenshots, bring them back in to
recreate these apps. So overall, the
entire experience just became way more
solid. So if you previously had some
lovable experience before with the new
agent mode, I suppose the only downside
is that some of these steps take a few
more credits, but more on that in the
end. It's not even that drastic. So
let's test this for the first time.
Create a new board. Okay, now these
buttons don't work. And I'll do the same
thing. And the important thing here is
to be precise. So I'm going to say on
the your keyboards site, the buttons
lead to 404 error pages. And I sent that
>> a few moments later.
Ah, there we go. Now it works. So let's
create a test board. Testing
uh new QA board. Test board AIA1, let's
say. And I allow anonymous questions.
Good feature. Okay. So, what about this?
If I click this, is it going to work? No
way. Okay. So, I can submit a question.
So, this would be what the audience is
looking at, right? So, where did you
grow up? And then I'm going to, you
know, add a name, which is optional. And
I'm going to leave out the email. Submit
question. Beautiful. So, now this is
where people can submit a question. And
then I suppose you could add more. Here
is a second question. I'm going to say
Eigor 2 test at
beautiful. And now I could upfold these
and yeah, if I just share this link with
my audience. Check this out. I mean, I
open up an anonymous browser, right? Put
it in here. Everybody in the audience,
every viewer could actually put their
questions here. So, if you want, you can
actually check out this page, submit a
question. But what I would do
practically as a creator is here with my
new test board. I could just use this
while live streaming. Viewers submit
questions here. They can upvote them and
I have it. No need for a subscription.
And guess what? If I want to customize
this, I could always add more features.
I could maybe add a community answer
feature where yeah, people can ask, but
also community members could answer it
right there and there. Something that
you're not going to get out of other
platforms. I could integrate AI
features. I could add payments. I could
improve the design, add various other
features, add a blog, do all of these
things to really make a fullfledged out
website. But the point of this video was
to showing you how quickly you can
generate relevant ideas without much
creativity at all. I used deep research
to do that and then build those ideas
with lovable. It really couldn't be much
simpler than this. And in total, I used
15 credits to build it to this stage. So
five credits you get for free. You can
try that right away and build something
on the free account. And if you want to
take it a little bit further and
actually get a production ready app like
this, you can totally do that. One more
note on the pricing here is that if you
click these three dots, you're going to
actually see how many credits used. So
this agent message used 2.6 credits and
that implemented the final product that
we're offering with this application
here. Right? This one used 2.5 and the
very first message, remember the long
one? That one actually only took 1.7
credits. So yeah, right there you can
see how simple Lovable is to use for new
users. And that's also the reason why it
has just gained this viral popularity
amongst people. It's just very
plug-andplay. And if you build something
interesting, feel free to share it in
the comments below. I'll be checking
those. And if you're still not sure what
to do, well, you can always scroll down
here on the Lovable page and see what
other people have built and then remix
their ideas. You could just take one of
these. And as you can see, already
17,000 people took this concrete
template and just customize it for
themselves. I hope this was interesting
to you. Thank you to Lovable for
partnering with us on this video. I had
a lot of fun and you can expect to see
this app in future live streams. And
with that being said, I hope you have a
wonderful